=Love Story in the 1970s=
=Episode 14=
Be careful.
Stop there.
Yes, there.
Chief Wang,
you bought a new cabinet?
It's a TV cabinet.
We'll come over to watch TV then.
Sure, please come.
Everyone's welcome.
Ms. Wang, I want
to watch TV at your place, too.
- Sure. You can come together.
- Me too.
You can all come together.
Go and play.
You bought a new cabinet?
Fei Ni.
My new cabinet.
It's specially for the TV.
I'm waiting for Fang Muyang
to get that TV coupon,
and then I can use it right away.
Chen's retirement report
has been approved.
Chen's retiring in a couple of days.
We made a deal.
Now
there aren't many days left.
I'll get going.
Come.
That's the glass panel, right?
Okay.
I'll carry it.
Go ahead. This way.
Watch your step.
Yes.
Okay.
Slowly.
Beside you.
Careful.
Yes. Behind you.
Watch your step. Behind you.
(Fei Ni,)
(you eat rice one bite at a time.)
(You walk the road step by step.)
(Don't you know)
(how much you can afford?)
Ting,
it won't work this time.
I can't help you.
Why are you back so late?
What's that?
206 Manual Turntable.
It may look a bit old,
but it sounds fine.
Why are you wasting money again?
Weren't we saving?
Don't get worked up yet.
I didn't buy it.
I borrowed it.
You...
What if someone finds out?
Five minutes.
Just five minutes.
How is it?
I took a long time to pick this record.
Do you like it?
Mozart?
Yeah.
♪Time quietly reveals♪
♪Those rising heartbeats♪
♪In my eyes, there's always a rainbow♪
♪Paving the road to our dreams♪
♪Those days and nights we shared♪
♪Are etched deep in memory♪
♪How I wish I could
write everything down♪
♪Your care, my love♪
♪Because of you♪
♪The ordinary days in my world♪
♪Turn bright♪
♪Rich and precious♪
♪How I wish I could♪
♪Be a firefly for you in the night♪
♪Guiding you toward the horizon♪
♪As you go to see a wider world♪
♪How lucky we are
to have chosen each other♪
♪Our hearts shine for each other♪
♪Let me become♪
♪A firework that shines for you forever♪
♪Burning with endless light♪
♪I'll tell our story with my life♪
♪Stars lean into the twilight,
you lean on me♪
♪For the rest of our lives,
let's not count the years♪
♪I'll walk beside you♪
I want to hear it again.
Again?
We've played it three times.
It's late.
Maybe I'll get another record.
We can listen to it later.
Okay.
Return it first thing tomorrow morning.
Keeping this here
is too dangerous.
Right.
I'll return it now.
Now?
Yes.
I'm leaving.
Well...
It's late now.
Where is he taking it?
Gao.
We can dismantle it now.
Fei Ni?
(Black-And-White TV Receiver
Repair and Adjustment)
You mean
you assemble a TV yourself?
Not just me,
Engineer Gao too.
It's Gao.
Just call me Gao.
Why do you look
so familiar?
I don't recall.
Fei Ni.
Gao is a key technician
at the No. 2 Electromechanical Factory.
He did us a huge favor.
He got all these parts, too.
Fang,
enough.
You'll sell me out.
Don't be nervous.
Fei Ni is my wife.
She's also the person I trust most.
She won't tell anyone.
Fang Muyang.
I'm stepping out for a second.
So the manual turntable
was for assembling the TV?
I didn't know that.
I even scolded you.
Sorry.
It's okay.
I was afraid it wouldn't work
and didn't want you to get your hopes up
for nothing,
so I didn't tell you about it.
There are so many parts.
They must've cost a lot.
Where did the money come from?
I borrowed it from Uncle Fu.
Return the money quickly.
We can afford the parts ourselves.
Okay.
What can I help with?
No need.
You have work tomorrow.
Go back and sleep.
No.
We're husband and wife.
We should share the burden.
I don't know much,
but I can help out a little.
Pass the tools,
or if you get hungry,
I'll cook something good.
Sure.
Come, Gao.
Here.
Fang Muyang.
Gao.
Food's ready.
Okay.
I'll help.
Wash your hands first.
♪Don't think too far ahead♪
♪Just work hard for today♪
♪Learn from the sun, how warm it is♪
♪Light up the corners that need it♪
♪The ones who smile the most♪
♪Gain the most in return♪
♪I want a life that's real♪
♪Steady, feet on solid ground♪
♪Slowly, our paths begin to cross♪
♪Each day holds something
to look forward to♪
♪Live it real♪
♪Two people, three meals, four seasons♪
♪Collecting ordinary moments in life♪
♪Making them into memories♪
(Teaching Building)
Fang.
Professor Wu.
We're about
to be transferred to our new posts.
You and Qu Hua
will be living apart.
Have you talked to him?
Not yet.
You're leaving soon,
and you still haven't told him?
I've made my decision anyway.
Sooner or later
makes no difference.
Fang,
I know you care a lot about your career.
But you have to balance
career and family.
Don't worry, Professor Wu.
I can handle it.
Alright.
I'll get back to work.
You're home.
Qu Hua...
There's something
I need to apologize for.
My project team has merged
with Jiangcheng University.
I'm transferring with them.
I'll leave tomorrow.
We'll probably be living apart.
Don't go.
Please.
Don't leave me.
I know this is unfair to you.
These past few days,
I've tried
to make it up to you
as much as I could.
I promise
whenever I get home leave,
I'll come back.
Okay?
Yan...
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I did my best,
but I'm useless. I...
I couldn't save you.
Yan...
I'm sorry...
I...
I saved so many people,
but I couldn't save you.
If only
you could've lived.
Yan...
Don't leave me...
Don't leave me.
No...
No, Yan...
Yan...
(Qu Hua)
This won't do.
I need to change it.
Change it.
How about this?
Let me try.
(Qu Hua, today I'm taking the train.)
(I've been transferred with
the team to Jiangcheng University.)
(Wishing you well.)
(Also,)
(Yan and I do look alike.)
Fang Mujing!
(Jiangnan)
I wanted a new TV.
This one's obviously old.
Who knows if it works?
Fang Muyang, are you messing with me?
Chief Wang,
I wouldn't dare.
Yes, it's not new,
but I guarantee it works.
Not only does it work,
but it also looks great.
Turn this knob.
This one?
To the right.
Slowly.
Okay.
Hear that?
There.
It's on!
That's great!
Great!
It's on!
Well...
About the money,
we won't talk about it now.
But there's nothing on the screen.
We forgot the most important thing.
If you don't pull out the antenna,
how will it get a signal?
There's a man!
A man on screen!
Look, Fei Ni!
There's a man on screen.
A man.
Everyone.
- Come to Chief Wang's unit to watch TV!
- There's a man.
Look.
It's quite clear.
Come on.
Quick.
Look.
That's great.
This is television?
Peking Opera.
Come watch.
Watch it like this.
Sit on the chair.
I'll bring you chairs.
Chairs.
I'll help you.
Chief Wang,
my brother...
I'll give you the money for the TV.
About your brother's job,
I can only recommend him.
The final decision rests with
the factory leaders.
Thank you, Chief Wang.
- Chairs. Chairs.
- Alright.
How's the picture?
Come.
Come. Sit and watch.
Come. Sit.
Watch this.
It's my first time watching TV.
Really?
Here.
Have some sunflower seeds.
Nice.
Thank you.
Come on.
(Welcome New Comrades!)
(Jiangcheng University)
Zhou.
Professor Wu,
you've finally arrived.
Welcome!
Zhou,
I've bought my whole team
over to your side.
I was counting the days.
You've finally bought your talents here.
Help with the luggage.
- This way, Professor Wu.
- I'll take it.
It's fine. I've got it.
Mujing,
I'd heard Jiangcheng University
was beautiful.
It truly lives up to its reputation.
(Jiangcheng College
Teaching Building No. 1)
(Welcome New Comrades!)
Fang Muyang,
you're amazing.
Come.
You can even build a TV.
Since you were little,
Ms. Chen said you were smart,
but you never put it to good use.
Let me.
You're not some kind of genius, are you?
Fang Muyang,
how can I ever thank you?
If it weren't for you,
my brother wouldn't have gotten the job.
I'll treat you to a meal.
Didn't you always want
steak and ice cream?
We'd have to go to
Deda Western Restaurant.
Maybe we can order a bottle of red wine.
Uh...
How about this?
I'll make you a new outfit.
Can I have
both of them?
I'm kidding.
Actually,
I have a way that doesn't cost money.
What is it?
Give me a kiss.
I was joking.
I didn't...
I'm going out.
Calm down.
I only did that to thank him
and to save money.
Everything happened too fast.
Fei Ni, just now, I...
Fang Muyang.
That was simply
my way of returning a favor.
Don't misunderstand.
We should
keep some distance
and treat each other with courtesy.
Alright.
As you say.
Would you like to sit?
No.
It's time.
I'm going to the canteen.
I'll get your lunch box.
Thank you, Comrade Fang Muyang...
You're welcome.
Comrade Fei Ni.
Well...
Please.
I need my meal ticket.
Yes, please.
See you, Comrade Fei Ni.
See you, Comrade Fang Muyang.
Let me.
You go ahead.
Alright.
(Jiangcheng No. 1 Textile Factory)
What are we promoting next?
That textile worker story.
Excuse me.
Here you go.
Just leave it here.
We'll share it.
See you.
Zhao.
Come.
Chief Wang.
What's it?
Check this draft one more time.
Okay.
Send it to Ms. Xu quickly.
Sure, no problem.
Report!
Who are you looking for?
Former educated youth Fei Ting,
from Second Company, Third Squad,
29th Regiment of Helongjiang
Production and Construction Corps,
reporting for duty.
Awaiting instructions, Madam!
Comrade Fei Ting is here.
There's no madam here.
We're all comrades.
Come on.
Let me introduce you.
This is
the new officer
in our Publicity Department,
Comrade Fei Ting.
Let's welcome him with applause.
Fei Ting,
that'll be your desk from now on.
Yes.
(Notes)
Ye Feng,
I borrowed all these
from the college library for you.
Island Female Militia is really good.
You'll like it.
You've seen the movie
Sparkling Red Star.
This is the novel.
Also very good.
Here are two sports books.
I borrowed these for you, too.
Let me see.
(Basketball)
What happened to your arm?
Nothing.
Those two books
were shelved too high.
I climbed a ladder to get them and fell.
I got a scrape.
Why didn't you put medicine on it?
I was worried you couldn't wait
if I took too long,
so I didn't bother.
Give me a second.
Does it still hurt?
It's fine.
Take this medicine
with you.
Keep applying it when you get home.
It's all my fault.
Had I known
you didn't like reading those,
I wouldn't have climbed up to get them.
I do like them.
I'll start reading them
as soon as I get home.
Ye Feng.
I like you.
You're good at basketball,
kind-hearted,
and have a strong sense of justice.
I do have quite a few strengths.
You're not bad either.
You're a college student, well-educated,
with a good personality,
and beautiful.
But
I'm not as good as Fei Ni, right?
Fei Ni is like these sports books.
(Basketball)
Thin,
but everyone likes them.
And I'm like these literature books.
Well-written,
but left high up on the shelf.
Ye Feng.
Can you tell me
why you loathe me?
I...
I don't loathe you.
I just don't like my mom
pushing you onto me.
If she hadn't interfered,
I might not have broken up with Fei Ni.
Ye Feng,
you don't have to like me,
but you can't look down on me.
Why do you mean "push me onto you"?
I'm a person,
not some object.
Yes.
I like you.
But you can't treat me like this.
That's not what I meant.
I'm sorry, Ling Yi.
Don't be angry.
Well,
I'm not good with words.
Don't cry, okay?
Guess I was deluding myself.
Ye Feng,
let's stop seeing each other.
Goodbye.
Ling Yi.
I used to see only Fei Ni
and overlooked someone
as excellent as you.
Ling Yi,
be my girlfriend.
Have you thought it through?
Yes, I have.
I think my mom was right.
You're no inferior to Fei Ni at all.
And you treat me so well.
If I don't like you,
I'd be blind.
Why aren't you wearing clothes?
I was washing up.
Look. I hung up a curtain.
No. I'm not looking.
Put your clothes on already.
I've put them on.
This
will be our private bathroom.
Look at this space.
Not for a full wash,
but it's fine for wiping down.
Want to try?
Don't worry.
I'll wait outside.
Fang.
Chief Cao.
Did you tick your wife off
and get kicked out?
It's cooler outside.
I'm done washing.
That space is really good.
But if the curtain were a bit taller,
it'd be better.
What...
are you looking at?
Fang Muyang.
It's wet here.
I...
I'll pour out the water.
Fei Ting, have some meat.
Thank you, Mrs. Lin.
You're welcome.
Fei Ting,
you really got into
Jiangcheng No. 1 Textile Factory?
It's not the factory.
The Publicity Department.
He'll be handling the writing.
I told you all along
Fei Ting had the ability.
You didn't believe me.
Look at this girl.
She doesn't know how to talk.
When did we ever say he didn't?
We just had expectations.
That was for your own good.
Am I right, Fei Ting?
Yes.
Your mom and dad mean well.
Right.
Dad, Mom, as we agreed before.
Once Fei Ting found a job,
you'd agree to our marriage.
Aunt can't marry him!
Why not?
My mom said
if Aunt marries him,
there'll be no hope for Dad's transfer.
Aunt has to marry someone
with connections.
Do you have connections?
Lin Jianshe,
what are you talking about?
I'm not lying.
I heard you say it.
Don't talk nonsense.
Go inside.
Fang Aihong, don't scold him.
Eat the dishes, Fei Ting.
Come on.
Fei Ting.
Your job is settled.
But how many legs do you have?
[* Refer to the quantity of furniture.]
I have
two.
Not those two legs.
We mean,
if you're marrying Lin Mei,
you need to prepare furniture, right?
Lin Mei
is so outstanding.
Shouldn't there be
at least thirty-six legs?
Dad, Mom, that's enough.
Are you centipedes?
What do you need so many legs for?
Can the house even fit that much?
If it doesn't,
I'll hang them from the beams.
Yeah.
Fei Ting,
that's the rule when our family
marries off a daughter.
But don't worry.
Once the legs are ready,
the wedding's on.
What rule is that?
You're making things hard for Fei Ting.
You're doing all these
to set me up with Wang Tengda,
so he'll transfer my brother
to the transport team.
Let me tell you.
Give up on that idea.
How can you talk
to your parents like that?
Don't make it sound like
we're harming you.
With Wang Tengda's condition,
if I hadn't
praised you in front of him,
he might not even have looked at you.
Perfect. Turtle matches mung bean.
Rotten fish matches rotten shrimp.
I like Fei Ting exactly as he is.
Mom.
You're a young lady.
Don't sound so harsh.
Your talk sounds nice, doesn't it?
One month.
Give me a month.
All the thirty-six legs.
Not one will be missing.
Sit down and eat.
Have some meat.
Here, eat the meat.
Did you see their faces just now?
So satisfying.
You should've shown
that spirit earlier.
Otherwise, they'd think
you're a pushover.
Don't worry yet.
I thought about it just now.
They said thirty-six legs,
but they didn't specify which legs.
We could make ten little stools.
That's forty legs.
Four extra for them.
That won't do.
Lin Mei,
your parents were right about one thing.
Marriage is a serious matter.
I want you to marry with dignity.
I want that, too.
But where are we going to get those?
Fei Ting,
if I have to wait another year or more
because of this,
I...
That won't happen.
I'll tell you the truth.
After I came to propose last time,
I called the secretary of  Qianjin Farm
and asked him to get some lumber.
I figured
with the money I had,
I couldn't manage thirty-six legs.
But if I could manage twenty-four,
it would at least be decent.
You used all your savings on lumber?
Are you silly?
You endured so much hardship and hunger
all those years
in Great Northern Wilderness
just to save that little money.
- You...
- That's not a big deal.
I saved it for our wedding anyway.
What worries me now
is that thirty-six legs.
I haven't saved enough.
I have some.
I'll withdraw it tomorrow.
No.
I can't take your money.
Aren't we family?
At this point,
why keep yours and mine separate?
Lin Mei,
I don't care how your parents see me.
But as their future son-in-law,
I want them to believe
I can give you a good life.
So
I have to solve it myself.
Didn't I say?
At most one month.
Have a little faith in me.
I've always had faith in you.
Don't let people see.
Let them see.
Who cares?
I saved this
for your wedding.
Use it first.
Ting,
this is the money Mom and Dad
saved for my wedding.
After buying furniture,
there are forty left. It's not much.
Wait.
Why are you all looking at me?
My money's all with your mom.
Dad,
that one...
Which one?
♪After the laughter, I think of you♪
♪After the storm, I think of you♪
♪In the little courtyard,
there you are dancing♪
♪That earnest you,
smiling so innocently♪
♪In spring, I stay by your side♪
♪When summer comes, I watch over you♪
♪In the light of dawn, you belong to me♪
♪At the edge of the world,
I will still hold you tight♪
♪There is a small place♪
♪Where they carry big dreams♪
♪Every lovely face♪
♪Shines brightly in the heart♪
♪Even when we collide,
we hold our course♪
♪Even when we stumble,
we keep our resolve♪
♪My you, walking toward the distance♪
♪Please carry our dreams
and let them soar♪